Aswinkumar Prakashkumar

1630 228th ST SE Apt I106, Bothell, WA – 98021 aswinkumar.p@outlook.com | 612-469-1282



Summary

Site Reliability Engineer with 8+ years of experience in managing large-scale distributed mission critical systems - associated automations, tooling, processes etc., Possess skills in Systems, Networking, Database, Capacity & Performance Analytics, and Chaos Engineering. Avid reader, blogger and technology enthusiast.

Skills

Linux (Redhat, Ubuntu, CentOS) and Windows Server Management, LXC,

Pivotal Cloud Foundry, REDIS, Cassandra, AWS (EC2, Route53, VPC), Hyper-V, SharePoint, Microsoft System Center Suite, TCP / IP Protocol, IP Telephony

(Cisco and Avaya), Nuance Voice Engine, VXML.

Monitoring and Logging : Grafana, Datadog, GENEOS, AppDynamics, Splunk, Kafka, and Logstash

Coding and Automation : Python, PowerShell, Chef, SALT, GIT, Jenkins, Sceptre (AWS)

Service Management : [Framework] ITIL v3, COBIT | [Tools] HPSD, Service Now

Experience

Infrastructure Engineering

Assoc. Software Engineer (SRE) | JP Morgan Chase & Co

Dec 2019 - Present

Part of a geographically distributed SRE team within JPMC's Cyber-Security and Technology Controls group, supporting various data protection products such as encryption / decryption, security modules etc.,

Sr. Site Reliability Engineer | T-Mobile (Indigo Slate)

May 2019 - Nov 2019

Supported speech & voice recognition applications within Voice Experience Product Development group, including but not limited to T-Mobile's S-IVR, a system that handled 125 million customers.

Guest Reliability Engineer | Target (Tata Consultancy Services)

Aug 2012 - May 2019

Have been part of teams - handling various production portfolios, including but not limited to End User Services (Hyper-V VDIs, Citrix Desktop Delivery, SharePoint etc.,), IP Telephony, Server Administration, etc.,

Responsibilities:

- Design, build, and maintain high availability and fault tolerant production infrastructure, and strategies for observability, logging, monitoring, chaos engineering, performance testing, etc.,
- Develop processes, tools, automation, and software changes to address operational issues, aimed at improving overall reliability.
- Leveraging modern engineering principles, such as Infrastructure as a Code, Containerization, Scripting etc., to improve developer / engineer's experience, and service deliverables.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Science and Engineering

Aug 2008 - May 2012

College: Meenakshi Sundararajan Engineering College, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Visa Information

Type: H-1B (First Arrival: March 27th, 2016) | Current Petition Validity: April 15th, 2022

GitHub LinkedIn Web Page
https://github.com/akprakashkumar https://www.linkedin.com/in/aswinpkumar/ www.aswinkumar.in